(my perfect stranger)
（我的完美陌生人）
(Kim Dong-wook)
（金东旭）
(Kim Ki-joo)
（金基珠）
(my perfect stranger)
（我的完美陌生人）
(part 1)
（第1部分）
When I think back it was a strange night.
当我回想起来 这真是一个奇怪的夜晚。
The vehicle is leaving the road. I'm going to change my route
车辆正在驶离道路。 我要改变路线了
Calculate new route.
计算新路线。
Everything that day was twisted in the most natural way
那天的一切 以最自然的方式扭曲
This doesn't happen every day.
这并不是每天都会发生的事情。
Crazy GPS system for bad weather
坏天气 疯狂的GPS系统
and mobile phone
和手机
(Yin Haejun)
（尹海俊）
That's when it popped up in front of me.
就在那时它突然出现在我面前。
oh oh!
哦，哦！
Ouch!
哎哟!
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
(time travel system)
（时间旅行系统）
(Time Travel System User Manual)
（时空旅行系统 用户手册）
There is an explanatory manual inside. How to use time machine
里面有一本解释手册。 如何使用时间机器
Yes
是的
The kind in novels or movies. A time machine like this.
小说或者电影里的那种。 类似这样的时光机器。
What's this?
这是什么？
I have been a journalist for seven years.
我当记者已经七年了。
I only pursue facts.
我只追求事实。
This is too idealistic for me.
这对我来说太理想主义了。
What kind of fantasy drama is this the protagonist of?
这是什么玄幻剧的主角？
I'm not interested in playing.
我没兴趣玩。
But there is one factor I overlooked.
但有一个因素我忽略了。
Curiosity led to my own nemesis.
好奇心导致了我自己的克星。
(Time Travel System, 2021)
（时间旅行系统，2021年）
(Time and space travel system, 3089)
（时空旅行系统，3089年）
(User Manual)
（用户手册）
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
The year 3089, do you want to know what I saw that year?
3089年， 想知道那一年我看到了什么吗？
That thing is not important. But what happens next is different.
那件事并不重要。 但接下来的事情就不同了。
(Time Travel System, 2021)
（时间旅行系统，2021年）
(Time travel system, 2037)
（时间旅行系统，2037年）
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
What will I see in 2037?
2037 年，我会看到什么？
What did I see there...
我在那里看到了什么...
what exactly is it?
到底是什么？
What do you see there?
你在那里看到什么？
have no idea
不知道
Anyway, after that incident
无论如何，在那次事件之后
My life started to go off track.
我的生活开始偏离正轨。
You see, I'm just here to talk nonsense. Now let's hear it.
你看，我就是来胡说八道的。 现在让我们听听。
(supermarket)
（超级市场）
I think my uncle has gone crazy.
我觉得叔叔已经疯了。
(Congratulations on becoming the host of the 1988 Seoul Olympics)
（恭喜您成为主持人 1988 年汉城奥运会）
What a pity, just listen to his uncle.
可惜了，就听他叔叔的话吧。
Do you still have what I just gave you?
我刚才给你的东西还在吗？
Yes
是的
I'll come back later to pay.
我稍后再回来付款。
If you want to eat something, eat it.
如果你想吃什么，那就吃吧。
- See you in 15 minutes. - Yeah.
- 15 分钟后见 - 是的
Friendly Neighbors Let the Village...
友好的邻居 让村...
It's a better place to live.
这是一个更好的居住地。
More and more teenagers are becoming addicted to hallucinogens.
越来越多的青少年对致幻剂上瘾。
From glue and butane gas
来自胶水和丁烷气
It comes in the form of bleach and benzene.
它以漂白剂和苯的形式出现。
Has emerged as a new drug among teenagers
已成为一种新型药物 在青少年中
Come and listen to the special report. from another reporter
来听听专题报道吧。 来自另一位记者
( BTW, My Perfect Stranger, Episode 1, 1987)
（ 顺便说一句，《我的完美陌生人》，第 1 集，1987 年）
I know you are really dedicated.
我知道你真的很敬业。
- You take good care of the old man. - Oh my God.
- 你把老人照顾得很好 - 天哪
- Oh - I really want to thank you.
- 哦 - 我真的要谢谢你。
- Oh come on - Oh my God.
- 哦 来吧 - 天哪
- Let's have a drink - Yes
- 我们喝一杯吧 - 是的
Okay, everyone.
好吧，大家。
as we all know
众所周知
Our Yujing Village was selected...
我们的雨井村被选中了...
Create a crime-free village for five consecutive years
打造无犯罪村 连续五年
Hey, there's clean water and it's peaceful.
嘿，这里有干净的水源，而且很平静。
Is this a good place to live? Do you all agree?
这是一个居住的好地方吗？ 大家同意吗？
- Agreed - Of course.
- 同意 - 当然。
Let's drink.
我们喝吧。
Is he an award winner?
他是获奖者吗？
I really enjoy being the center of attention.
我真的很喜欢成为关注的焦点。
Mazuto
真烦人
Brothers too
兄弟也
- It's nice to see him happy. - It's good for the ghost.
- 很高兴看到他高兴 - 这对鬼魂有好处
The Village that Makes Us It's a great place to live.
在使我们的村庄 这是一个非常适合居住的地方。
most important player
最重要的球员
and be respected by everyone in our village
并受到尊重 我们村里的每个人
- The light of our people - Oh my God!
- 我们人民的光芒 - 天哪！
Please meet Principal Yoon Byung-koo...
请见见尹秉九校长...
and our committee chair
和我们的委员会主席
- Oh my god - Go ahead.
- 天哪 - 继续吧
- This guy said you don't have to do this. - No.
- 这个人说你不必这么做 - 不
- Say something - Come on
- 说点什么 - 来吧
- What does the principal have to say? - Yes.
- 校长有什么要说的？ - 是的。
Oh, thank you.
哦谢谢。
- Great
- 太好了
But I did nothing.
但我什么也没做。
First of all, I want to thank the villagers. Yuting Village
首先，我要感谢村民们。 雨亭村
Very good people are capital.
非常优秀的人就是资本。
second
第二
I want to thank our children for growing into such wonderful people.
我要感谢我们的孩子 成长为如此优秀的人。
This is simply not true.
这根本不是真的。
No wonder it ended in tragedy.
难怪 最终以悲剧告终。
Because even though we know very little about each other
因为尽管我们彼此了解甚少
But you still believe each other with your eyes closed.
但你们仍然闭着眼睛相信对方。
What are you talking about him?
你在说他什么？
- what did he say? - How is this going?
- 他说什么？ - 这是怎么回事？
About 30 seconds later
大约30秒后
You will hear a scream. It came from the mountains behind.
你会听到一声尖叫。 是从后面的山上传来的。
Six naughty teenagers...
六个淘气的少年……
They will begin to split up and run in six directions.
他们将开始分头向六个方向奔跑。
Everyone was super drunk.
每个人都喝得超级醉。
And three of these six are girls from this village.
以及这六个中的三个 是这个村子里的一个女孩。
What is he saying?
他在说什么？
Are there any children in our village who are drunk after drinking glue?
我们村里有喝胶水喝醉的孩子吗？
Maybe not?
也许不会？
Television reporters had clues before the incident.
电视台记者在事发前就已经掌握了线索。
Departing from Seoul
从首尔出发
- TV reporter?
- 电视记者？
Five minutes later, the reporter arrived.
五分钟后，记者就到了。
You have approximately 4 minutes and 30 seconds.
您大约有 4 分 30 秒的时间。
You need to solve this problem. before reporters arrived
你需要解决这个问题。 在记者到达之前
Who are you? You don't look like anyone here.
你是谁？你看起来不像这里的任何人。
How dare you interrupt? Our picnic and such accusations
你怎么敢打扰？ 我们的野餐和这样的指责
Kim Hae- kyung, sixth grader, one room, Woojeong High School
佑正高中 六年级一间房金海京
My middle daughter was in that room.
我的二女儿就在那个房间里。
- My classmate Lee Eun Ha - My Eun Ha?
- 我的同学李恩河 - 我的恩河？
Our sweet little girl?
我们可爱的小女儿？
Another classmate, Park Yuri
另一位同学，朴尤里
Wait, that's my niece.
等等，那是我的侄女。
Are you sure you want to take the risk?
您确定要冒这个险吗？
According to the Toxic Substances Control Act...
根据《有毒物质管理法》...
- What? - What's that sound?
- 什么？ - 那是什么声音？
- Is that the sound of people screaming? - Yes, it's coming from over there.
- 是人们尖叫的声音吗？ - 是的，从那边传来。
Has it been 30 seconds?
已经过了 30 秒了吗？
This story is about our children.
这个故事是关于我们的孩子的。
Let's believe him.
我们相信他吧。
No, that's not true at all.
不，这根本不是真的。
I did nothing.
我什么也没做。
Oh my god.
天啊。
Drink, the water here is still clean.
喝吧，这里的水还是干净的。
Who are you?
你是谁？
Missed a step on the cliff over there…
错过了那边悬崖上的一步……
It was her destiny to end her life at the age of 19 .
而19岁结束自己的生命， 就是她的命运。
I just changed it to
我刚刚将其更改为
Who are you...
你是...
very handsome
很英俊
- What's this? Hey, good girl... - Eun-ha, oh my god.
- 这是什么？嘿，好女孩…… - 恩哈，天哪。
- Unbelievable, you crazy kid. - Galaxy
- 难以置信，你这个疯狂的孩子。 - 银河
- This kid - Oh my God.
- 这个孩子 - 天哪。
- Please calm down - you crazy person.
- 请冷静 - 你这个疯子
- pay attention - oh, look at that
-注意点 -哦，看看那个
- This is unbelievable. - Let's go.
- 这太难以置信了 - 我们走吧
Go straight and hurry up.
直走，快点。
- Come on. - Here.
- 快点走吧 - 在这里
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
- Attention - Grandma, grandpa.
- 注意 - 奶奶，爷爷。
- What did you do... what did you do? - What?
- 你做了什么...你做了什么？ - 什么？
- Oh my God, what happened?
- 天哪，发生了什么事？
Come quickly.
快点过来吧。
- Come on oh my God - Let's go
- 过来吧 哦 天哪 - 我们走吧
- come here - stop
- 过来 - 停下来
- He... - What?
- 他... - 什么？
Do I need to push?
我要推一下吗？
The one who tricks other kids into smelling glue is you.
欺骗其他孩子闻胶水的人 就是你。
She may make herself appear to be in danger.
她可能会让自己看起来处于危险之中。
But others actually had to die.
但其他人实际上不得不死。
I don’t want to help a misbehaving kid. Who killed two of his own friends?
我不想帮助一个行为不端的孩子。 谁杀了他自己的两个朋友？
If you really want this, just say so.
如果你真的想要这样，就直说吧。
I'll help you push it down.
我会帮你推下去的。
What is this bastard?
这混蛋是什么？
Can you forget about it for a while?
你能暂时忘掉一下吗？
("10 out of 10 glue sniffers killed two people")
（“十分之十的胶水嗅探器 两人死亡”）
Wait a moment.
等一下。
Let's go and see.
我们去看看吧。
Oh, I was totally shocked.
哦，我完全震惊了。
- Oh my God - Damn, they survived.
- 天哪 - 该死，他们活了下来。
He saved her.
他救了她。
Because your mother is different from other people. So I think my life is very difficult.
因为你的妈妈和其他人不一样。 所以我觉得我的生活很艰难。
What?
什么？
What do you want to know?
你想知道什么？
Although her mother was a little different, she...
虽然她的母亲有些不同，但她...
I live for you.
我为你而活。
So don't do such a thing. with friends again
所以不要做这样的事情。 再次和朋友们在一起
do you understand?
你明白吗？
I don't want to do that either.
我也不想这么做。
even without you
即使没有你
There are still people in this village who are helping. there are more
这个村子还有人帮忙。 还有更多
Wow!
哇！
- Hello - Hero of Yujing Village
- 你好 - 雨井村英雄
Astonishing.
惊人的。
the best.
最好的。
Above knows who to send to us.
上面知道该派谁给我们。
("Wujing Village was selected as the village that has been crime-free for five consecutive years)
（“乌井村被选为 该村连续五年无犯罪）
Oh, Dad.
哦，爸爸。
Oh my gosh, did you just remember that?
天哪，你刚刚想起来了吗？
The next news story is about unruly teenagers.
下一个新闻故事是关于不守规矩的青少年的。
has become a serious social problem
已经成为一个严重的社会问题
Here are high school students who get drunk on glue.
这里有喝胶水喝醉的高中生。
Oh my God, where have they all gone?
天哪，他们都去哪儿了？
God, be careful.
天啊，小心点。
Ouch!
哎哟!
How can we thank you enough?
我们该如何感谢你才够呢？
This is just a temporary illusion.
这只是一时的错觉。
They were still in high school.
他们还只是高中生。
Parents should comfort and guide them well.
家长要安慰 并好好引导他们。
Because that's what adults should do.
因为那是 成年人应该做的事情。
You said exactly what I thought.
你说的就像我想的一样。
You know these things. How are you?
你知道这些事情。 你怎么？
Know exactly what will happen when.
确切地知道什么时候会发生什么。
It all happened like that.
一切都像那样发生了。
That's it.
就是这样。
-Uncle- Oh.
- 叔叔 - 哦。
Hidehiro Hidezen
英浩英善
Teacher, you just dropped it.
老师，你刚才把它掉了。
I?
我？
(Teaching Certificate)
（教学证书）
- Pretty much the same thing. - What?
- 几乎就是一件事 - 什么？
I put it down.
我放下了它。
Oh, really.
哦真的吗。
Teacher Yoon Haejun?
尹海俊老师？
Are you a teacher?
你是老师吗？
Yes
是的
He accidentally moved from Seoul. The time to come to our village is just right.
他不小心从首尔搬来了。 来我们村的时间正好。
- What? - Really?
- 什么？ - 真的吗？
That is...
那是...
Sorry for asking.
抱歉问了。
But have you found a new job?
但你找到新工作了吗？
Not yet, not yet.
还没有，还没有。
There is a vacancy at the school I am currently in charge of .
我现在负责的学校 有一个空缺职位。
- Oh, is that right? - Yes.
- 哦，是这样吗？ - 是的。
What kind of coincidence could this be?
这会是怎样的巧合呢？
I teach Korean.
我教韩语。
Yes, Teacher Yin.
是的，尹老师。
This was the beginning of my fake life.
这就是我虚假生活的开始。
In 1987, in that village
1987年，在那个村庄
(teacher's office)
（教师办公室）
(Korean language)
（朝鲜语）
- Teacher, - go away.
- 老师， - 走开。
Go away.
走开。
I'm the first one here, teacher.
我是第一个来的，老师。
teacher
老师
I've become someone I never wanted to be.
我已经成为了 我从来不想成为的人。
That's the teacher
那是老师
and bought a house in a remote village
并买了房子 在一个偏僻的乡村
Something I never wanted to buy before.
以前从来不想买的东西。
I lived like this for a whole month.
我就这样生活了整整一个月。
Why do I have to do this?
为什么我必须这样做？
(Seoul 2021)
（2021 年首尔）
The Yujing Village Serial Murder Case happened in 1987
雨井村连环杀人案 那件事发生在1987年
The man you killed 34 years ago...
34年前你杀死的那个人...
Still alive in that place
还活着在那个地方
No, I didn't kill them.
不，我没有杀他们。
I know.
我知道。
What?
什么？
That's why I went there. Find out the real culprit
这就是我去那里的原因。 找出真正的罪魁祸首
This way you and I can survive.
这样你我都能活下去。
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
You'll be released tomorrow morning , right?
明天早上 你就会被释放，对吗？
Let's meet in Yujing Village.
我们在雨井村见面吧。
I'll tell you what I'm talking about.
我会告诉你我在说什么。
Then before tomorrow morning...
那么明天早上之前...
This also helps with survival.
这也有助于生存。
("The murderer of the Youjing Village serial murder case committed suicide")
（“佑井村连环杀人案的凶手自杀了”）
("The murderer of the Gojing Village serial murder case will be released tomorrow.")
（“五井村连环杀人案的凶手明天将被释放。”）
Mr. Yunyong, where are you?
云勇先生你在哪里？
Is it coming?
它来了吗？
(Editor-in-Chief)
（主编辑）
I know today is your holiday.
我知道今天是你的假期。
But the teacher only called Teacher Yin Ying. what can I do?
但老师只叫了尹英老师。 我能做些什么？
I will arrive soon.
我快到了。
I realized I couldn't rest.
我意识到我无法休息。
(Mother)
（母亲）
what else?
还有什么？
Is it a video this time?
这次是视频吗？
What is this about?
这是关于什么的？
This is the video.
这就是视频。
Singing was very cute when I was a child .
小时候 唱歌很可爱。
Mom was worried because it was swollen.
妈妈很担心，因为它很肿。
My son told me to convert it to a file. You can put it in a USB.
我儿子告诉我将其转换为文件。 您可以将其放入 USB 中。
I understand, I will do the same next time.
我明白了，下次我也会这么做。
I committed to doing this for over a year.
我承诺要这样做一年多。
I didn't forget on purpose.
我不是故意忘记的。
Are you still busy these days?
这些天你还忙吗？
My child must be very tired.
我的孩子一定很累了。
But how late is it now? Are you going home today?
但现在已经晚到什么时候了？ 今天你回家吗？
today?
今天？
Why do we celebrate our father’s birthday every year?
为什么我们每年都要庆祝父亲的生日？
Mom used to get flowers from him. On your birthday?
妈妈常常从他那里得到花。 你生日时？
He rarely comes home.
他很少回家。
Preparing food for him was always just the two of us.
为他准备食物 永远只有我们两个人。
Because his father is very busy.
因为他的父亲很忙。
what are you busy with?
你在忙什么？
Busy, drunk, having trouble hanging out with friends?
忙碌、喝醉、 与朋友相处有困难？
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
Mom can cook a lot of delicious food.
妈妈会做很多美味的食物。
I also make my kids’ favorite mixed vegetables.
我也会做我孩子最喜欢的杂菜。
This doesn't have to be difficult. Because I won't go.
这并不一定很困难。 因为我不去。
I will send you more money.
我会寄更多的钱给你。
You should go buy some new clothes and get some fresh air.
你应该去买一些新衣服 ，呼吸一下新鲜空气。
Stop watching old videos, they are so depressing.
别再看旧视频了， 它们太令人沮丧了。
That's it.
就是这样。
Just asking: Why is the murderer in my novel...
就是问： 为什么我小说里的凶手是……
Even if it’s only women?
即使只有女性？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
An old aunt like me comes to write novels
像我这样的老阿姨来写小说
You must not find it strange, right?
大家想必并不觉得奇怪吧？
Just like any man in this world...
就像这个世界上任何一个男人一样...
can murder
可以谋杀
Any woman can kill a man. It's also cruel.
任何女人都可以杀死男人。 也很残酷。
I only choose stories...
我只选择故事...
I'm more familiar with it. Let's turn it into a novel.
我比较熟悉的 我们把它写成小说吧。
If so, let's move on to the next question.
如果是这样，我们进入下一个问题。
(Author discussion with writer Gao Meishi)
（作者讨论 与作家高美石)
This is your first novel. Published 1987
这是你的第一部小说。 1987年出版
"small door"
《小门》
This is the teacher's only novel...
这是老师唯一的小说……
There is no murderer there
那里没有凶手
Mr. Yin Ying's favorite novel is here.
尹英先生最喜欢的小说来了。
Yes, it led me to this hell.
是的，它把我带进了这个地狱。
A novel that I both love and hate.
一本让我又爱又恨的小说。
This story was written by a teacher when I was only nineteen years old.
这个故事是老师写的 ，当时我才十九岁。
Isn’t it boring to talk about the past?
谈论过去不无聊吗？
Rather than talk about this, I'd like to...
与其谈论这个，我想...
Introducing the most important people in my life now
介绍最重要的人 现在我的生活中更多
over there in the back
在后面那边
See that sparkly girl?
看到那个闪闪发光的女孩了吗？
She is a personal editor. I mentioned it before
她是个人编辑。 我之前提到过
Also my soul mate.
也是我的灵魂伴侣。
Most of my successes...
我的大部分成功...
I got it because of her dedication.
我因为她的奉献而得到了它。
I can not believe it. Who planned this event?
我简直不敢相信。 谁策划了这个活动？
I haven't been able to write much lately.
我最近没能写太多东西。
And asked me to answer nonsense questions.
还让我回答废话问题。
When do we talk about old novels?
我们什么时候谈论老小说？
Some novels have sold more than a million copies. There are more volumes
有些小说的销量已超过一百万册。 还有更多卷
I'm still talking about my first bad piece.
我还在谈论 我的第一个糟糕的作品。
Oh, and look at your own work again.
哦，再看看你自己的作品。
do not you know?
你不知道吗？
How many people became fans because of the teacher's first novel?
有人成为粉丝 有多少是因为老师的第一本小说？
This is me. who became the first fan
这就是我。 谁成为第一个粉丝
If it weren't for the sentences in the teacher's novel, I would...
如果不是 老师小说里的句子，我会……
Hey, do you think I'm interested in her?
嘿，你觉得我对她感兴趣吗？
So let's go back to the office, okay?
那么我们回办公室吧，好吗？
Please take some of the pressure off me.
请让我减轻一些压力。
Oh, my daughter.
哦，我的女儿。
What?
什么？
I'm going to start the car now.
我现在就去发动车子。
This kid is so cold.
这孩子实在是太冷了。
Do I want more money?
我要更多的钱吗？
I just want to see your face.
我只想看看你的脸。
This doesn't mean...
这并不是说...
I rewatch the video because I have no money so I will die.
我重看视频 因为我没有钱，所以我会死。
Oh my god.
天啊。
Oh, it's so expensive.
哦，这么贵啊。
Hello
你好
Sorry to keep you waiting.
很抱歉让您久等了。
- Can I see number 36? - Can.
- 我可以看看 36 号吗？ - 可以。
What about restaurants?
那么餐厅呢？
I made a reservation at the store across the street.
我在街对面的商店预订了房间。
You can go as soon as Ena arrives.
惠那一到你就可以去。
I sent the address to Teacher Park.
我把地址发给朴老师了。
Did you see the introduction I sent you?
你看到我发给你的介绍了吗？
Don't you see the dark circles under your eyes?
你没看到你眼睛下面的黑眼圈吗？
I read it all night until I couldn't sleep. It's really fun.
我读了一整夜，直到无法入睡。 真的很好玩。
Slightly relieved.
稍稍松了口气。
This time, he won't be torn to pieces.
这一次，他不会再被撕成碎片了。
She hates my job in many ways.
她在很多方面讨厌我的工作。
No, Master, why do you say that?
不，师父 为什么这么说呢？
There will be a good response. Only after her verification.
将会收到良好的反响。 只有经过她的核实之后。
So I can't really complain.
所以我真的不能抱怨。
But anyone can check and fix this problem.
但任何人都可以检查并解决这个问题。
Of course, all writers are teachers.
当然，所有作家 这就是老师。
Bring it with you.
带上它。
It will go well this time, Master. I can feel.
这次一定很顺利，主人。 我能感觉到。
It is often said that good shoes will take you to good places.
人们常说，好鞋 会带你去好地方。
Why is she wearing those shoes?
她为什么穿那双鞋？
-Run away- I want a pair.
- 逃跑 - 我想要一双。
- What shoes? - let me see.
- 什么鞋？ - 让我看看。
Mother?
妈妈？
-Stop. -Don't push.
-停下来 -别推
- Don't push me. - Be careful.
- 别逼我 - 小心点
It's like a flea market.
这就像一个跳蚤市场。
Just some stupid shoes on sale. Why all the fuss?
只是一些愚蠢的鞋子在打折。 为什么要大惊小怪呢？
- What’s wrong with you? - bring it on.
- 你怎么了？ - 来吧。
- Yes, this is the sixth one. - Sorry.
- 是的，这是第六个 - 抱歉
Life is so miserable.
人生实在是太悲惨了。
- Very beautiful - Size 6.5
- 非常漂亮 - 尺寸 6.5
Even though people are poor, they still need to have a certain standard.
人虽穷，也要有一定的水平。
You should remember this before you get older.
在你变老之前，你应该记住这一点。
- Mom - Oh.
- 妈妈 - 哦。
Are you OK?
你好吗？
What should we eat today? I'm starving.
今天我们应该吃什么？ 我快饿死了。
I may not have eaten anything yet. Because you have to follow your mom, right?
我可能还没有吃过任何东西。 因为你必须跟着你妈妈，对吗？
I'm probably waiting for you, let's go.
我可能正在等你，我们走吧。
Brother, let’s go first and talk after dinner.
哥，我们先走吧 ，吃完饭再聊。
Yes
是的
Oh my god.
天啊。
oh
哦
Mother
母亲
real
真的
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
Aren't you afraid of cars?
你不怕车吗？
I'm hard of hearing. I've called several times.
我听力不好。我打过几次电话了。
Mom is thinking about this problem. How much did you spend today?
妈妈正在思考这个问题。 今天你花了多少钱？
I know, don't raise your voice.
我知道，别提高声音。
I didn't raise my voice.
我没有提高声音。
Hey, cool, try this.
嘿，很好，试试这个。
what else?
还有什么？
If it doesn’t fit, try it on quickly. Mom will take it to change.
如果不合适就赶紧试穿。 妈妈会带它去改变。
Do you want me to give it to you too?
你想要我也给你吗？
No, talk about it later.
不，以后再说。
- I don't want - oh, this child.
-我不想要 -哦，这个孩子
He said I would try again later and got up.
说我稍后再试试，就起身了。
I know, okay.
我知道，好吧。
- Are you satisfied? - Perfect fit, right?
- 你满意吗？ - 非常合适，对吧？
Or is it because your daughter is beautiful?
还是因为你女儿漂亮？
The shoes look shiny.
鞋子看起来闪闪发亮。
It is often said that good shoes will take you to good places.
人们常说，好鞋 会带你去好地方。
Who would believe such a thing? It's just nonsense.
这种事谁会相信？简直是无稽之谈。
Hey, these are not cheap shoes.
嘿，这不是便宜的鞋子。
Mom doesn't buy it. From the store where the child met the mother, stand up and look.
妈妈不买。 从孩子见到妈妈的那家商店，站起来看看。
Mom went to their store and bought it at full price.
妈妈去他们店里全价买了。
This is good stuff.
这是好东西。
I said nothing here.
我在这里什么也没说。
Who told you to buy it?
谁叫你买的？
I told my mother to take the money. Go buy some beautiful clothes for yourself?
我告诉妈妈把钱拿走。 去买漂亮的衣服给自己穿吧？
Mom has no place to show off.
妈妈没有地方可以炫耀。
That is why.
正是因为如此。
So don't dress like this...
所以不要穿成这样...
- What's this ?
- 这... - 什么？
How many times have I told you to throw it away?
我告诉过你多少次把它扔掉了？
Why do you love this decade-old vintage scarf?
你为什么喜欢这条保留了十年的老式围巾？
Look at other people around you.
看看你周围的其他人。
Who wears such clothes? look.
谁穿这样的衣服？你看。
I should never have bought it for my mom in the first place.
我一开始就不应该给我妈妈买的。
I get it and my ears are going to explode. Don't shout.
我明白了，我的耳朵快要爆炸了。 别喊。
Do you embarrass your child so much?
你让你的孩子这么尴尬吗？
I only work with smart, level-headed people.
我只和聪明、头脑冷静的人一起工作。
People like mothers are a laughingstock to their children.
像母亲这样的人对于孩子来说就像是笑柄。
Why do you say that?
为什么这么说？
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
Even if your child is wearing dirty shoes and an old-fashioned scarf
即使你的孩子穿着脏鞋 和一条老式围巾
A mother never neglects her child.
母亲永远不会忽视自己的孩子。
that's right...
这是正确的...
No matter what your child wears or does. A mother never neglects her child.
无论您的孩子穿什么或做什么。 母亲永远不会忽视自己的孩子。
do you understand?
你明白吗？
And mom...
还有妈妈...
The mother doesn't know how to play with her child either.
妈妈也不会和她的孩子玩。
Mother
母亲
then...
当时...
If I didn't let my mother go like this...
如果我不让我妈妈就这样走的话...
real
真的
Will anything change?
会有什么改变吗？
I don't play either.
我也不玩。
- Do you want this bag? - Yes.
- 你想要这个包吗？ - 是的。
I think there's plenty of time to make up for this.
我觉得时间还很充裕 足以弥补这一点
(Screenwriter Gao Meishu)
（高美淑 编剧）
(Sunday, May 9)
（5 月 9 日，星期日）
(Turn off the power)
（关闭电源）
Oh, it's me. Did you have meal?
噢，是我。你吃饭了吗？
Because I'm still a mother.
因为我还是一个母亲。
Because one person is a mother...
因为一个人就是母亲...
He will always be waiting for us no matter what.
无论何时，他都会一直在等我们。
Mother
母亲
(Invitation card to the wedding of Baek Hee-seop and Lee Sun-ae)
（参加婚礼的邀请卡 白熙燮和李善爱）
Hello
你好
Yes, I'm talking.
是的，我正在说话。
But mom...
但妈妈...
my mother...
我的母亲...
There seems to be a suicide note.
似乎还有一封遗书。
Mother
母亲
in the past...
在过去...
I used to miss that day in this world. Don’t you have a mother?
我曾经怀念这个世界的那一天 你没有妈妈吗？
Mother...
母亲...
Mommy mommy.
妈妈妈妈。
I don't want it.
我不想要它。
- Now on Earth - Mother
- 现在在地球上 - 母亲
"Mother"
“母亲”
Mother...
母亲...
When I say this word...
当我说这个词的时候...
- No one answered - That's not true
- 没有人回答了 - 那不是真的
(May 9, writer Gao Meishi)
（5月9日， 作家高美石）
(I've lost my patience with you)
（我对你已经失去耐心了）
(You may need to find another publisher.)
（您可能需要寻找其他出版商。）
(delete)
（删除）
Still can't contact your father?
还是联系不上你父亲？
I don't understand why you come here?
我不明白 你为什么来这里？
In this Wujing Village
在这个乌井村
I've never heard of it before.
我以前从未听说过。
And it's also far away from our home.
而且离我们家也很远。
(Police Detective)
（警探）
We still need to investigate further.
我们还需要进一步调查。
But you should check this out.
但你应该看看这个。
I think he intended to send it to his daughter.
我认为他打算将其发送给他的女儿。
(Father)
（父亲）
Father
父亲
Is that Yoon Young?
那是尹英吗？
Her father was in trouble again.
她父亲又惹麻烦了。
I won't give in this time.
这次我不会屈服。
Do you know how many plates he broke?
你知道他打碎了多少盘子吗？
Ah what?
啊什么？
Oh, don't puke there.
哦，别吐那里。
really too much
真的太多了
Oh my god.
天啊。
Send me the account number and amount.
把账号和金额发给我。
Compensate for all losses he has promised so far
赔偿所有损失 他迄今为止所承诺的
I'll forward it to you now.
我现在就转给你。
I'm afraid you won't come.
恐怕你不会来。
No, I'm worried you won't come.
不，我担心你不会来。
I felt a little relieved.
我稍微放心了一点。
who are you?
你到底是谁？
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
You have to ask.
你得问清楚。
How do I know? You are not a bad person...
请问我怎么知道呢？ 你不是坏人...
Since 34 years ago, or...
从34年前开始，或者...
how could I know...
我怎么知道...
The night before being released...
被释放前一天晚上...
You will hang yourself.
你会上吊自杀。
I told you the answer last night.
昨晚我已经告诉你答案了。
I think I'll believe it. Are you talking nonsense?
我想我会相信的。 你胡说八道吧？
Do you really want me to believe that you really went back in time?
你真的想让我相信 你真的回到过去了吗？
alright.
好啦好啦。
Because I've been rotting in prison for thirty years.
因为我已经在监狱里腐烂了三十年了。
So I thought of making fun of it.
于是我就想到了取笑它。
I don't know about this. Real world, damn?
我不知道这件事。 现实世界，该死？
There are still 16 years to go.
距离现在还有16年。
I plan on going head to head. And retired at a young age
我打算正面交锋。 并且年纪轻轻就退休了
I will go fishing, read books...
我会去钓鱼、看书……
In such a quiet village I want to continue playing.
在这样一个安静的村庄里 我想继续玩。
That used to be my dream.
那曾经是我的梦想。
This was the path I chose.
这曾经是我选择的道路。
But by 2037 , that is, 16 years later.
但到了2037年 ，也就是16年后。
I want to see my simple dreams come true. is this real?
我想看到我简单的梦想成真。 这是真的吗？
I'm just going to check it out and come back.
我只是去看看然后就回来。
(Time Travel System, 2021)
（时间旅行系统，2021年）
(Time travel system, 2037)
（时间旅行系统，2037年）
However...
然而...
I can not do it.
我做不到。
My dream cannot come true.
我的梦想无法实现。
Because I died young
因为我英年早逝
one year from now
从现在起一年后
I will die at the age of 35.
我将在 35 岁那年去世。
Do you want to know about my death? What does this have to do with you?
你想知道我的死吗？ 这和你有什么关系？
because...
因为...
The villain who killed me is the real villain...
杀了我的恶棍才是真正的恶棍......
In Serial Murder Case Yujingcun, 1987
在连环杀人案中 雨井村, 1987
how do you say?
你怎么说？
What is that about...
那是关于什么的...
(Bangbang Tea House)
（棒棒茶馆）
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
That was the symbol of the 1987 villain.
那是1987年反派的象征。
It was also found at the scene of my murder.
在我被谋杀的现场也发现了它。
Of course you are the first. police are looking for
当然你是第一个。 警方正在寻找
but you...
但是你...
He even died before me.
他甚至比我先死。
You said you didn't kill anyone.
你说过你没有杀过任何人。
can't stand injustice
并不能忍受不公正
The night before you were released, it was yesterday
你被释放的前一天晚上 这是昨天
You hanged yourself in your cell.
你在牢房里上吊自杀了。
impossible
不可能的
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
That doesn't make sense at all, does it?
这根本不合理，不是吗？
How can a dead man kill me?
一个死人怎么能杀我？
So I decided to believe you were innocent.
所以我决定相信你是无辜的。
how do you say?
你怎么说？
Can I believe it?
我可以相信吗？
This is the real villain.
这才是真正的恶棍。
Can we really find it?
我们真的能找到吗？
You have to get it.
你必须得到它。
How did I drive off the road?
我怎么把车开出了公路？
This is the only way. You and I will have a chance...
这是唯一的办法。 你和我将有机会...
have a proper life
有一个适当的生活
(To Yin Ying)
（致尹英）
Yoon Young
尹英
I'm sorry I made you angry.
很抱歉我让你生气了。
And mom...
还有妈妈...
The mother doesn't know how to play with her child either.
妈妈也不会和她的孩子玩。
After the children move out
孩子搬出去后
Mother
母亲
Mom couldn't help but lament that we were drifting apart
妈妈忍不住感慨 我们渐行渐远
Mom may be trying to appear angry.
妈妈可能想表现出生气的样子。
Oops, the frogs are singing.
哎呀，青蛙在唱歌。
Son, grandson, daughter-in-law
儿子、孙子、儿媳
let's get together
让我们欢聚一堂
Singing all night long but no one wanted to listen.
整夜唱歌 但没有人愿意听。
During this time, my mother no longer missed me. I couldn't do it as a kid.
这段时间，妈妈不再想我了。 我小时候做不到。
when the child was young
孩子小的时候
My kids used to sing the frog song.
我的孩子曾经唱过青蛙之歌。
I will always play with you.
我会永远和你一起玩。
Even if my mother turns into a gray-haired grandma
哪怕妈妈变成了白发苍苍的奶奶
I play with my mother every day.
我每天都会和妈妈一起玩。
That's why I have to play...
这就是为什么我必须玩...
-Your little mouth used to talk all the time. -For me too. All right.
-你的小嘴以前总是说个不停。- 对我来说也是。好吧。
Baby’s little hands are so cute
宝宝的小手好可爱
Oh no, no.
哦不，不。
Ouch!
哎哟!
If mom could travel through time and space
如果妈妈可以穿越时空
Mom also wants to...
妈妈也想...
Go back to that time and hold those hands again
回到那个时候 再握住那双手
cute little hands of child
孩子可爱的小手
Yoon Young
尹英
Mom will never forget.
妈妈永远不会忘记。
If only my mom could do it.
如果我妈妈能做到的话。
Mom wants to play with her baby...
妈妈想和她的孩子一起玩...
For the rest of my life , until my mother turns into a gray-haired grandma.
我的余生 ，直到母亲变成白发苍苍的奶奶。
From this mother who loves her children
来自这位爱孩子的母亲
(Bangbang Tea House)
（棒棒茶馆）
"Book" right?
“书”吧？
(Book...)
（书...）
That is...
那是...
Yoon Young
尹英
Why didn't my mother answer the phone when she called me?
妈妈打电话给我时，她为什么不接？
Before my mother passed away, she called my father three times.
母亲去世前，给父亲打了三通电话。
Are you ignoring your mother again?
又不理你妈了是吗？
let's go.
我们走吧。
We should start from here. Let's go find the children's mother.
我们应该从这里出发。我们去找孩子们的母亲吧。
Where can mom go?
妈妈可以去哪里？
How can we find mom?
我们怎样才能找到妈妈呢？
- Yunying- Dad.
- 允英 - 爸爸。
Do you know why I keep wanting to leave? Away from hometown
你知道我为什么一直想离开吗？ 远离家乡
Because I hate seeing father and mother living together.
因为我讨厌看到 父亲和母亲住在一起。
That's why.
这就是原因。
When we're together, we argue.
当我们在一起时，我们会争论。
Every time we quarreled my father then left the house.
每次我们吵架的时候 父亲随后离开了家。
And mom will always wait for dad.
而妈妈会永远等待爸爸。
I hate seeing this every day. To escape from there
我讨厌每天都看到这个。 为了逃离那里
Even though I know in the end my mother will be alone.
尽管我知道最后 母亲将独自一人。
But my mother said she missed me.
但妈妈说她想我。
If mom could go back in time
如果妈妈能回到过去
Mom was stupid enough to say she would come find me again.
妈妈傻到说她会再来找我。
I am...
我是...
I want to go back in time. Dad, you can really go back.
我想回到过去。 爸爸，你真的可以回去了。
If I could turn back time
如果我能让时光倒转
I would take the long way back.
我会走很远的路回去。
This way mom doesn't have to...
这样妈妈就不用...
love daddy
爱爸爸
Or love me again
或者再爱我一次
Mom doesn't have to live with anyone...
妈妈不用和人住在一起...
This makes my mother feel lonely and deceives her into waiting for a lifetime.
这让母亲感到孤独 骗了妈妈一辈子的等待
I will make my mother happy...
我会让妈妈幸福...
Finish life by yourself
自己走完人生
I will let mom live.
我会让妈妈活下去。
But I can't.
但我做不到。
Because it's impossible
因为这是不可能的
If you become obsolete, you will die.
如果你过时了，你就会死。
I'll buy you something better than this. Let's go to the mall together.
我会给你买比这个更好的东西。 我们一起去商场。
Expensive things are not necessarily good things, but this one is beautiful.
贵的东西不一定是好东西，这个就漂亮了。
This is my mom's favorite.
这是我妈妈最喜欢的。
The color suits you well too.
颜色也很适合你。
My daughter uses her salary. Start with your first part-time job
我女儿用她的工资。 从第一份兼职工作开始
Come and buy it for me.
快来给我买吧。
With these little hands...
用这双小手...
Oh, I'm disappointed with the money. But you can buy it for me.
哦，我对钱很失望。 但你可以给我买。
it's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
My daughter goes to college near here.
我女儿在这附近上大学。
I'm here to visit your university.
我来这里是为了参观 你们的大学。
It is because of my daughter that I was able to go to college.
正是因为我的女儿， 我才能考上大学。
- You must be happy - Yes
- 你一定很高兴 - 是的
Who knew this day would come?
谁知道这一天会到来呢？
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
Lay a piece of silk in my heart and stand at the end of your alley
在我心里铺上一块绸布 站在你小巷的最后一端
I will welcome you with beautiful candles.
我会用美丽的蜡烛欢迎你。
I turned into a butterfly and walked on the fragrant flower road
我变成了一只蝴蝶 走在芬芳的花路上
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
（ 2021年至1987年的时间旅行系统）
I will fly and stop in your heart.
我会飞翔，停在你的心里。
Our words become songs and poems.
我们的言语变成歌曲和诗歌。
I'll sing to you after laying the carpet on my heart
我会唱歌给你听 在我的心里铺上地毯之后
Do you know what that feels like?
你知道那是什么感觉吗？
my carpeted heart
我铺着地毯的心
Lay a piece of silk in my heart and stand at the end of your alley
在我心里铺上一块绸布 站在你小巷的最后一端
I will welcome you with beautiful candles.
我会用美丽的蜡烛欢迎你。
Wait a moment.
等一下。
ha!
哈！
Hey!
嘿！
That day, I brought the shoes my mother bought for me.
那天，带着妈妈给我买的鞋子。
Where are they taking me?
他们要带我去哪里？
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(首尔莫0508)
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
（ 2021年至1987年的时间旅行系统）
welcome
欢迎
(Celebrating the Seoul Olympic Games)
（庆祝汉城奥运会举办）
- Is there a problem? - This way, please.
- 有什么事吗？ - 请这边走。
Not that expensive.
没那么贵。
Come on, try it first.
来吧，先尝试一下。
It's well worth it.
这是非常值得的。
Really good.
真的很棒。
(teahouse haha)
（茶馆哈哈）
(Moon and Sun Gramophone)
（月亮和太阳留声机）
(vinyl records, cassette tapes, picture books)
（黑胶唱片、盒式磁带、图画书）
Ouch!
哎哟!
excuse me
打扰一下
oh!
哦！
May I?
可以吗？
Yes
是的
Your forehead is bleeding too.
你的额头也在流血。
What's wrong with my shoulder?
我的肩膀怎么了？
It's not like that.
不像那样。
I am fine.
我很好。
Wait, what happened?
等等，怎么了？
Your face is also pale.
你的脸色也苍白。
You should go to the hospital.
你应该去医院。
It's not because of you.
这不是因为你。
Just focus on yourself.
只要专注于你自己。
Don't break your word, do you understand?
说过的话就不要食言，明白吗？
Alas, am I exercising too hard?
唉，是不是我运动太辛苦了？
Almost gone
快没了
(Baek Hee-seop)
（白熙燮）
(moon night)
（月夜）
(Family endurance walking competition Yujing Village, third time)
（家庭耐力步行比赛 雨井村，第三次）
Even if she disappears far away
就算她消失得很远
like the wind blowing
就像吹过的风
Please stop for a moment.
请稍事停留。
We will also play the most modern songs.
我们还将演奏最现代的歌曲。
There is also a band performance at midnight.
午夜还有乐队表演。
Sorry, I'm very tired today.
对不起，今天我很累。
Can you let me pass?
你能让我过去吗？
There is something going on with friends.
和朋友之间有事。
It must have been painful to watch.
看着一定很痛苦。
There is no reason to join the club. What's better than relieving stress?
没有理由加入俱乐部。 还有什么比缓解压力更好的呢？
Why does everyone have to get in my way?
为什么每个人都要挡我的路？
Are you interested?
你对此感兴趣吗？
I heard the rewards are good.
听说奖励不错。
If you finish third, you'll also get a Walkman.
如果你获得第三名，你还将获得一个随身听。
My sister and I are going to participate in the competition tomorrow.
明天我和姐姐要参加比赛。
That number was entered incorrectly, right?
那个号码输入错误了，对吗？
What day is tomorrow?
明天是几号？
"May 10th" Sunday
“5月10日”星期日
Does it have to be "Day 4" instead of "Day 3"?
必须是“第四天” 而不是“第三天”？
This is not that story, "1987."
这不是那个故事，“1987年”。
It’s already 2021.
现在已经是 2021 年了。
What's this? I am afraid.
这是什么？我害怕。
Is it really painful?
真的很痛苦吗？
(May 10, 1987)
（1987 年 5 月 10 日）
(Meet So Bangcha at Moon Night Club)
（在月夜俱乐部与 So Bangcha 见面）
(Moon Nightclub)
（月亮夜总会）
Brother, you go home, I won't disturb you anymore.
哥，你回家吧， 我不打扰你了。
Is this really 1987?
这真的是1987年吗？
The 1988 Olympic Games will be held next year. I really do not know.
1988年奥运会将于明年举行。 我真的不知道。
club?
俱乐部？
Do you really want to go to the club?
真的想去俱乐部吗？
Then...
然后...
I think it's too late now. Shall we go to the amusement park?
我想现在已经晚了。 我们去游乐场好吗？
Not really, but so what?
确实不是，但是怎么样呢？
We are still just students.
我们还只是学生。
"We are still just students."
“我们还只是学生。”
Hey, Li Shanai wants to praise herself as an excellent student?
喂，李善爱要夸 自己是优秀学生吗？
In a few days, we will be 20 years old.
再过几天，我们就20岁了。
Go clubbing for a few months first. What would that look like?
先去泡吧几个月。 会是什么样子呢？
And one more thing...
还有一件事...
They had just been caught sniffing glue.
他们刚刚被抓到嗅胶水。
Will it really be okay?
真的会没事吗？
Therefore...
正因为如此...
So we have to take her with us.
所以我们必须带她一起去。
Please be careful when you talk to your mother this time .
这次和妈妈说话的时候， 请小心点。
We went to study together...
我们一起去读书了...
Staying at your house all night, do you understand?
整晚都在你家，你明白吗？
I don't like lying.
我不喜欢说谎。
this
这
Do we really have to take this girl with us?
我们真的必须带这个女孩一起去吗？
that's right.
这是正确的。
She must be complicit. To keep our stories consistent
她一定是同谋。 为了让我们的故事保持一致
Last time she told my mom we didn't travel together.
上次她告诉我妈妈 我们没有一起旅行。
So I was beaten almost to death by my mother.
于是我就被我妈打得差点死了。
I must die...
我必须死...
Before marrying Hae Sung hyung?
在和海成哥结婚之前？
understand
理解
But will you let this girl go on like this?
但你会让这个女孩就这样下去吗？
No more we don't want to be kicked out...
不再 我们不想被赶走...
From entrance to club
从入口到俱乐部
Oh my God, this is...
天啊，这是……
what do I do?
我该怎么办？
(Quan Yingnuo)
（全英诺）
This would say...
这会说...
This year is 1987?
今年是1987年？
If you are sick, go to the hospital.
如果你生病了，就去医院。
Don't do this in front of someone else's store.
不要在别人的商店前这样做。
real
真的
If you're joking, you have to have boundaries.
如果你在开玩笑，你就必须有界限。
Have I ever told you I'm not in the mood right now?
我有没有告诉过你我现在没心情？
Is this a filming location?
这里是拍摄地吗？
Where are we now?
我们现在到底在哪里？
yes...
是...
This is Wujing Village.
这里是乌井村。
I don't know what "shooting location" means?
我不知道 “拍摄地点”是什么 意思？
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
I can find the answer myself.
我自己就能找到答案。
oh
哦
what is that?
那是什么？
(Please check the connection and try again)
（请检查连接 然后再试一次）
No signal here?
这里没有信号吗？
Can't access the Internet here?
这里不能上网吗？
what is it?
它是什么？
- no signal? - What signal?
- 没有信号？ - 什么信号？
What's going on around here?
这附近发生了什么事？
Brother, please come back , don't come back again.
兄弟，请你回来吧 ，不要再回来了。
Damn, I almost dug my own grave.
妈的，我差点给自己挖坟了。
- Is it this one? - Yes.
- 是这个吗？ - 是的。
unless...
除非...
- we look great - let 's go
-我们看起来棒极了 -我们走吧
damn it.
该死的。
Learn to watch horses and boats.
学会看马、看船。
Yes, sorry.
是的，对不起。
Oops, the frogs are singing.
哎呀，青蛙在唱歌。
Son, grandson, daughter-in-law
儿子、孙子、儿媳
let's get together
让我们欢聚一堂
Singing all night long but no one wanted to listen.
整夜唱歌 但没有人愿意听。
Mother
母亲
This is real.
这是真的。
Sorry, I'll explain everything.
抱歉，我会解释一切。
Yes
是的
You're probably still in shock right now.
您现在可能仍处于震惊之中。
But it's worse than you think.
但情况比你想象的还要糟糕。
We just...
我们刚刚...
Back in 1987.
时间回到1987年。
And there is no way...
而且没有办法...
You can go back.
你可以回去了。
We're stuck here.
我们被困在这里了。
is this real?
这是真的吗？
Yes
是的
Oh my god.
天啊。
Don't be too scared.
别太害怕。
I will do everything...
我会做一切...
If this is the case...
如果是这样...
It's true, damn.
这是真的，该死。
sorry.
对不起。
are you laughing?
你在笑吗？
(Thanks to actor Kim Hye-eun)
（感谢演员金惠恩）
(And actor Kim Hyun-mok who was invited to perform)
（和演员金贤莫 谁被邀请表演）
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
（ 2021年至1987年的时间旅行系统）
(my perfect stranger)
（我的完美陌生人）
This is real?
这是真的？
Is my mother still alive?
我的母亲还活着吗？
- Mom - Don't do this.
- 妈妈 - 别这样做。
Do you want to hit me?
你要打我吗？
Mom, what's wrong? Why did I hit you?
妈妈，怎么了？我为什么打你？
Okay, we're going to start hitting. Youth is gone
好的，我们要开始打击了。 青春已然
What are kids like you doing here?
像你这样的孩子在这里做什么？
- Come here quickly - You are not a student of our school
- 快点过来 - 你不是我们学校的学生
Yes, that's you.
是的，就是你。
Why do you have to pretend not to know?
为什么一定要假装不知道呢？
Are you here to travel?
你是来旅游的吗？
Why did you enter the club?
你为什么进入俱乐部？
He suddenly looked at me...
他突然看着我...
I don't know what your name is.
我不知道你叫什么名字。
My name is Baek Hee-seop.
我叫白熙燮。
(Conclusion)
（结语）
Where have you been so late?
这么晚了你去哪儿了？
Yuting Village
雨亭村
Wujing Village?
乌井村？
Yuting Village is your hometown?
雨亭村 你的家乡？
Why did you end up there all of a sudden?
怎么突然就到那里去了？
fit...
合身...
Something needs to be resolved.
有件事需要解决。
(my perfect stranger)
（我的完美陌生人）